在上一个视频中，我们使用 fix 是客户端进程
in the previous video we used fix is the client process
向质押服务器进程发送消息
to send messages to the pledge server process
我们通过添加一些来模仿我们在性方面所做的事情
we've mimicked what we did in sex by adding some
质押服务器底部的代码
code to the bottom of pledge server ex
它在质押服务器模块之外
it's outside of the pledge server module
就在这里
just right down here
除了 larry moan curly
and in addition to larry moan curly
我们又增加了两个承诺
we've added two more pledges
共五项承诺
for a total of five pledges
然后我们发送消息以获取最近的承诺
then we send a message to get the recent pledges
我们有一个接收块
and we've got a receive block
捡起那些
that picks those up
如果我们运行它
and if we run that
果然我们有五项承诺
well sure enough we have our five pledges
所以在这种情况下，我们有两个进程进行通信
so in this context we have two processes communicating
所有这些代码都在质押服务器模块之外
all this code outside of the pledge server module
这里将在客户端进程中运行
right here is going to run in the client process
然后服务器进程是这样的
and then the server process is this
产生的监听循环
listen loop that gets spawned
好的，现在我们要封装
okay so now we want to encapsulate
创建和获得最近的承诺
creating and getting recent pledges
在这些注释功能中
in these commented functions right here
所以让我们从第一个箱子承诺开始吧
so let's just start with this first one crate pledge
所以现在
so right now
它将承诺发送到外部服务
it's sending the pledge to the external service
然后兑现
and then cashing it
但这发生在我们的内部
but that happens up inside of our
在服务器进程中运行的监听循环
listen loop which runs in the server process
就在这儿
right here
那么创建质押功能需要做什么
so what the create pledge function needs to do
只是向我们的服务器进程发送消息
is just send a message to our server process
送入坑
send to a pit
消息是
and the message is
创建承诺
create pledge
名称和金额
name and amount
并让它发挥作用
and for that to work
我们将不得不传入 pid
we're going to have to pass in the pid
我们将把它作为
we'll pass it in as the
这个函数的第一个参数
first argument to this function
所以这将在客户端进程中运行
so this is going to run in the client process
接着
and then
这部分将在服务器进程中运行
this part is going to run in the server process
现在在这里我们可以调用我们的 crate 质押函数
down here now we can call our crate pledge function
所以我们称之为质押服务器
so we call pledge server
创建承诺
create pledge
第一个参数必须是 pid
the first argument needs to be the pid
服务器进程，由 spawn 返回
of the server process and that was returned by spawn
所以我们已经有了一个 pid 变量
so we have a pid variable already
就这样
just like that
我们把它存起来
we save that away
好吧，它就像以前一样工作
well it works just like it did before
现在让我们实现最近的承诺功能
now let's implement the recent pledges function
我要拿
and I'm going to take
这段代码和我们一起
this code here with us
让我们就在这里
let's right up here
我们会不寻常的
we'll uncommon it
和那个函数的主体
and the body of that function
我们需要做两件事
we need to do two things
我们需要向服务器进程发送消息
we need to send a message to the server process
然后立即等待回复消息
and then immediately wait for a response message back
从该服务器
from that server
所以这个功能也需要走坑
so this function also needs to take a pit
我们将向该 pid 发送消息
we'll send to that pid the message
最近的承诺告诉它发送回复给我们
recent pledges telling it a send the reply back to us
然后我们会
and then we'll
有一个收到承诺的收据
have a receive which picks up the pledges
而不是在这里做 io 和 spec
and instead of doing io and spec right here
我只想回报承诺
I just want to return the pledges
所以因为这个模式匹配
and so because this pattern matches
我们运行它
we run this it
给我们承诺，这隐含地是
gives us the pledges and that's implicitly going to be
函数的返回值
the return value of the function
最近的承诺
recent pledges
现在要记住的一点是，虽然罪
now something to keep in mind here is although the sin
是同步发送
is a synchronous sending
消息始终是同步的
a message is always a synchronous
接收是阻塞调用
receive is a blocking call
它将等待服务器的响应
it's going to wait for a response from the server
所以这个函数作为一个整体
so this function as a whole
将是同步的
is going to be synchronous
所以现在在这里我们可以用
so now down here we can replace all this with
质押服务器
pledge server
最近的承诺
recent pledges
通过那个pid
passing that pid
这将归还给我们的承诺
and that's going to return to us the pledges
我只是要使用 io
and I'm just going to use io
检查返回列表
inspect to inspect the returned list
把它存起来
save that away
再次运行它，我们仍然看到所有五个承诺
run it again and we still see all five pledges
但我们只想得到最近的承诺
but we only want to get recent pledges
我们会说这是最后一个
which we'll say is the last
三项承诺或
three pledges or
列表中的前三个承诺
the first three pledges in the list
我们会在这里解决这个问题
we'll fix that up here
当我们得到一个我们想要采取的新承诺时
when we get a new pledge we want to take
最近的两项承诺
the two most recent pledges
并将新的承诺添加到列表的头部
and add the new pledge to the head of the list
使新状态有三个承诺
so that the new state has three pledges
为此，我们将在此处添加一行
so to do that we'll add a line here
假设最近的承诺
let's say most recent pledges
并且menu模块有take功能
and the menu module has a take function
我们想从状态中获取列表
we want to take from the state that's a list
最近的两项承诺
the two most recent pledges
所以这会给我们一个最多有的列表
so that's going to give us a list that has at most
里面有两个元素
two elements inside of it
然后我们想把
and then we want to put
新的承诺在该清单的首位
the new pledge at the head of that list
这是我们要添加的新承诺
so here's the new pledge that we're adding
我们将把它添加到这个列表中
we're going to add it to this list
这最多会给我们
and that's going to give us at most
列表中的三个元素
three elements in the list
把它存起来
save that away
再次运行它
run it again
果然我们有优雅的雏菊和卷曲的
and sure enough we've got grace daisy and curly
所以现在我们已经开始运行了，我们感觉真的
so now that we have this running and we feel really
舒服
comfortable with it
我们可以删除调试语句
we can remove the debug statements
或打印到屏幕上的 put as 语句
or the put as statements that print out to the screen
那里也将删除等待消息
there and also will remove waiting for message
但这确实让我们想知道
but that does leave us wondering
如果发送到外部服务失败怎么办
what if sending to the external service fails
客户如何知道质押是否成功
how will the client know if the pledge was successfully
创建与否
created or not
客户进程想知道这一点
the client process would like to know about that
所以我们需要发送消息
so we need to send a message
背部
back
向客户端进程指示成功或失败
to the client process indicating a success or failure
我们实际上知道如何做到这一点
and we actually know how to do that
是的，我们只需要包含客户的 pid
yeah we just need to include the client's pid
在消息中
in the message
所以这将是发件人
so this will be the sender
然后我们需要回复那个发件人
and then we need to reply back to that sender
所以一旦我们弄清楚了新的状态
so once we have the new state figured out
我们会说发送
we'll say send
给发件人
to the sender
我们会给它一个消息标签响应
we'll give it a message tag response
然后我们要发回这个 id 变量
and then we're going to send back this id variable
再一次，那只是
again that's just
创建的质押的一些唯一标识符
some unique identifier for the pledge that was created
那么我们需要改变
then we need to change
这在这里创建质押功能
this create pledge function right here
所以它需要将自己作为第一个发送
so it needs to send self as the first
此消息元组的元素
element of this message tuple
然后就像
and then just like
最近的承诺
recent pledges
它需要等待响应
it needs to wait for a response
所以我就在那里复制那个接收块
so I'll just copy that receive block right there
而不是承诺
instead of pledges
这实际上将是
this is actually going to be
我们就称它为这个状态
we'll just call it this status
现在两个函数都是同步的
and now both functions are synchronous
然后在底部，因为
then down at the bottom because
这些现在返回一个状态
these now return a status
好吧，我将添加一个 io
well I'll just add an io
检查所有这些行的前面
inspect to the front of all those lines
现在如果我们运行它
and now if we run it
我们所看到的我们实际上得到了承诺 4 6 9
what we see we actually get pledge 4 6 9
以及针对不同承诺的不同唯一 ID
and different unique ids for different pledges
所以我们得到了他们被创建的迹象
so we get an indication that they were created
然后最后我们看到我们最近的承诺
and then the end we see our recent pledges
当我们在制作函数时
while we're making functions
让我们包装或封装
let's wrap or encapsulate
在名为 start 的函数中生成
the spawn in a function named start
我喜欢把它放在模块的顶部
I like to put it at the top of the module here
我们称之为开始
we'll call it start
现在我们有粘贴了
now there's paste in what we have
但在那之前我要打印出来放我们
but before that I'm going to print out put us
启动 pled 服务器
starting the pled server
好的，那么我们要生成质押服务器
all right then we want to spawn the pledge server
我需要使用服务
I need to use serve
保证服务器在那里监听循环
pledge server there to listen loop
和以前一样
just the same as before
然后在客户端下
and then down in the client
我们可以这样做
we can just do this
血液服务器启动
blood server start
这同样有效
and that works just as well
现在可以了，但这是一个巧妙的技巧
now that works but here's a neat trick
如果在某个时候我们决定改变
if at some point down the road we decide to change
我们在这里使用的模块的名称
the name of the module which we use right here
那么我们需要记住改变这个产卵线
then we'll need to remember to change this spawn line
使这更灵活
to make this more flexible
我们可以使用下划线下划线模块
we can use underscore underscore module
下划线 下划线
underscore underscore
并且在编译时这将被替换或扩展
and at compile time this will get replaced or expanded
带有当前模块的名称
with the name of the current module
在这种情况下，请参见 dot plug server
which is see dot plug server in this case
这仍然有效
and that still works
所以现在如果我们看看下面的客户端代码
so now if we take a look at the client code down here
好吧，我们看到了
well we see that
更容易扮演客户的角色
it's easier to play the role of a client
它不需要
it doesn't require
任何有关消息结构的知识
any knowledge of how messages are structured
或来回发送
or sent back and forth
客户端和服务器进程之间
between the client and server processes
这意味着我们可以改变
and that means we can change
服务器进程的内部细节
the internal details of the server process
不影响客户端代码
without affecting the client code
一件事你可能
one thing you probably
虽然注意到了这个客户端代码
noticed about this client code though
是我们必须通过pid
is that we have to pass the pid
到每个功能
to each of the functions
因为我们只打算拥有一个
and since we only plan to have one
在任何给定时间运行的质押服务器进程
pledge server process running at any given time
绕过坑有点多余
passing the pit around kind of feels redundant
是的，客户端界面会很多
yeah the client interface would be a lot
如果我们可以删除更简单
simpler if we could remove
所有对 pid 的引用
all references to the pid
所以我们想摆脱那些
so we'd like to get rid of those
以及最近的承诺
and also right here for recent pledges
但问题是客户端将如何运作
but then the question is how would the client functions
知道在哪里发送他们的信息
know where to send their messages
事实证明
well it turns out
很容易注册我们的服务器进程 pid
it's easy to register our server processes pid
以任意名称
under an arbitrary name
然后使用那个名字
and then use that name
向服务器发送消息时
when sending messages to the server
我们将在我们的开始函数中做到这一点
and we'll do that up in our start function
在流程模块上
on the process module
有一个函数叫寄存器
there's a function called register
它需要一个 pid
it takes a pid
然后它需要一个名字，名字必须是一个原子
and then it takes a name and the name must be an atom
我要使用质押
I'm going to use pledge
下划线服务器，但这完全是任意的
underscore server but this is totally arbitrary
是的，如果另一个错误将引发
and yes an error will be raised if another
进程已经注册了同名
process has already registered with the same name
然后我们还将返回 pid
and then we'll also return the pid
以防万一来电者想要它
just in case the caller wants it so
现在我们已经注册了我们的服务器进程
now that we have our server process registered
在这个名字下
under this name
这里插件服务器
here plug server
在这些功能中，例如创建质押
down in these functions like create pledge
我们可以删除 pid 作为参数
we can remove the pid as an argument
然后当我们打电话时
and then when we call
发送而不是发送到 pid
send instead of sending to the pid
我们可以发送到服务器的名称
we can send to the name of the server
以同样的方式，我们可以从最近的承诺中删除 pid
in the same way we can remove pid from recent pledges
然后我们就发送到那个名字
and then we just send to that name
很酷，仍然有效
cool that still works
现在这样做的一个缺点是如果你决定改变
now one downside of this is if you decide to change
路上的名字
the name down the road
很容易忘记改变
it's easy to forget to change
一次出现
one occurrence
所以你可能记得改变这个
so you might remember to change this one
但不是这个
but then not this one
所以这是另一个技巧
so here's another trick
我们可以使用模块属性
we can use a module attribute
这样注册的名字就是
so that the registered name is
只在一处
only in one place
现在我将在名称处使用模块属性
now I'll use the module attribute at name
那只是我编造的
that's just something I made up
这是相当传统的，但你可以称之为
it's fairly conventional but you could call this
如果需要，进程名称
process name if you wanted
这只是一个任意名称
it's just an arbitrary name
然后我们将与之关联
and then we'll associate with that
atom质押服务器
the atom pledge server
所以基本上我们现在只有一个概念
so basically we just have a concept now
然后我们可以使用 at name
and then we can use at name
引用注册名称
to reference the registered name
所以我们要注册我们的pid
so we're going to register our pid
以 pled 服务器的名义
under the name pled server
然后我们必须确保也改变这些
and then we have to make sure to also change these
这将是名字
this is going to be at name
这个也一样
and so will this one
但它的美妙之处在于你不必改变
but the beauty of this is you don't have to change
如果您想更改名称，这些在路上
these down the road if you want to change the name of
你的过程
your process
您只需在此处更改这一行
you just change it on this one line right here
一切都流过
and everything flows through
所以保存它应该可以工作
so save that away it should work
果然如此
and sure enough it does
现在在继续之前
now before moving on
我们会评论
we'll comment
质押服务器模块底部的代码
the code at the bottom of the pledge server module
因为我们只是
since we're just
用它来踢质押服务器的轮胎
using it to kick the tires of the pledge server
我们也不希望这段代码运行
and we also don't want this code to run
当我们在下一节中启动时
when we fire up in in the next section